Guide to the Scott Marshall Papers TAM.851
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Scott Marshall Papers
1985-2023
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Marshall, Scott
TAM.851
1.67 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes
1 audiocassette
1 VHS-C
670.45 Megabytes in 165 computer files
Scott Marshall is a trade unionist and longtime leader within the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA). He is a vice chair of the CPUSA and chair of the party's Labor Commission. He has worked with CPUSA since 1987 when he became a district organizer for the party in Illinois. He remained in that role until 1997 when he was elected as the chair of the National Labor Commission. Scott's introduction to movement work began in the 1960s as a high school student in Virginia, where he was active in the Civil Rights movement and in anti-war activism. As a trade unionist he participated in reform movements amongst rank-and-file members of the Teamsters, Machinists, and Steelworker unions, and remains active in SOAR (Steelworkers Active Organized Retirees). He was also a founder of the Jobs or Income Now (Join) organization and the National Congress of Unemployed Organizations. The Scott Marshall Papers (dated 1985-2023) consists of materials created and collected by Marshall documenting his work as the district organizer for CPUSA in Illinois. Materials include correspondence and ephemera, but the majority of the collection consists of Marshall's notes and notebooks from the 1980s and 1990s. In addition to Marshall's involvement, the materials also document the factional struggle and split within the party in 1991. The collection also includes electronic photographs of CPUSA National Committee events, and recordings of sessions from the Party's Think Tank initiative.
Scope and Contents
The Scott Marshall Papers (dated 1985-2023) consists of materials created and collected by Marshall documenting his work as the district organizer for the Communist Party in Illinois. Materials include correspondence and ephemera, but the majority of the collection consists of Marshall's notes and notebooks from the 1980s and 1990s. In addition to Marshall's involvement, the materials also document the factional struggle and split within the party in 1991. The collection also includes electronic photographs of CPUSA National Committee events, and recordings of sessions from the Party's Think Tank initiative.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Scott Marshall in January 2025; the accession number associated with this gift is 2025.053.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Biographical Note
Scott Marshall is a trade unionist and longtime leader within the Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA). He is a vice chair of the CPUSA and chair of the party's Labor Commission. He has worked with CPUSA since 1987 when he became a district organizer for the party in Illinois. He remained in that role until 1997 when he was elected as the chair of the National Labor Commission. Scott's introduction to movement work began in the 1960s as a high school student in Virginia, where he was active in the Civil Rights movement and in anti-war activism. As a trade unionist he participated in reform movements amongst rank-and-file members of the Teamsters, Machinists, and Steelworker unions, and remains active in SOAR (Steelworkers Active Organized Retirees). He was also a founder of the Jobs or Income Now (Join) organization and the National Congress of Unemployed Organizations.
Communism -- Illinois.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.; Labor movement.; Communism.; Marshall, Scott; Communist Party of the United States of America (Ill.); Communist Party of the United States of America. National Labor Commission
- Classes Taught, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CPUSA National Convention, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Global Think Tank -- Correspondence, Drafts, Notes, 2006-2023 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Global Think Tank -- Ephemera, 2007; TW_TAM_851_ER_3
- Global Think Tank -- Manufacturing Think Tank Audio Recordings, cuid44253
  - Analog Audio Recording -- Day 1 and 2 #6, cuid44254 (Box Shared Tamiment 195, Audiocassette cuid44254)
  - Electronic Recordings, 2008; TW_TAM_851_ER_2
- Ideological Conference, 1999; cuid44252 (Box Shared Tamiment 172, Vhs-c cuid44252)
- Illinois District, 2001-2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Labor Secretary, 1999-2010 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Lightfoot, Claude -- Photograph Taken by Scott Marshall, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mesaba Range Cooperative Park Association, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- National Committee Photographs, 2011; TW_TAM_851_ER_1
- Notes -- General, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12-14, Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Notes -- Big Picture Unionism, circa 2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notes -- Illinois District, Labor Research Association, National Convention, 1985-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Notes -- Meetings, 2003-2010 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
- Notes -- Meetings, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
- Notes -- National Committee, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notes, Speeches, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Notebook, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Notebook, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Notebook, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Notebook -- To-Do and Weekly Plan, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notebook, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Notebook, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Notebook, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Notebook, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Notebook, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Notebook -- China, North Korea, National Board, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Notebook -- Cuba, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Notebook -- Illinois Board, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Notebook, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Notebook -- National Board, Russia Report, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Notebook -- Loose Pages, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Notebook, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Notebook -- GDR Notes, Bilateral Meetings, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Notebook -- National School, Gus Hall Presentation, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Notebook -- Notes on Interviews in Russia, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 11)